<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2374">
  <number>33</number>
  <name>Diagnostic evaluation reports</name>
  <summary>&lt;p&gt;If a screening session indicates that an ELL may have a learning disability, the next step is performing a diagnostic evaluation. Remember, screening only indicates the likelihood of a learning disability, so it is critical that a follow-up diagnostic evaluation is completed to determine if a disability truly exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to screenings, diagnostic tests are available in Spanish with the use of a translator if the psychologist is not fluent in Spanish. Again, keep in mind that the translator should only be used if their responses will be unbiased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A learning disability diagnostic report can offer a wide variety of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Report details may include some or all of the following information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear and specific identification of a learning disability stated in the documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation of a developmental and educational history consistent with a learning disability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardized measures of academic achievement and cognitive processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional limitation(s) in one or more of the following areas of academic achievement:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="Bullet"&gt;-   Reading (decoding, fluency, and comprehension)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Bullet"&gt;-   Mathematics (calculations, math fluency, and applied reasoning)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Bullet"&gt;-   Written Language&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation of relative strength(s) in academic achievement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation that shows alternative explanations for the academic limitations have been considered and ruled out (e.g., low cognitive ability, lack of adequate instruction, and emotional factors, such as anxiety or depression)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation of weaknesses and strengths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation on accommodations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence></sequence>
  <visible>0</visible>
  <availabilityjson>$@NULL@$</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>0</timemodified>
</section>