<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2376">
  <number>35</number>
  <name>Help for performing diagnostic evaluations</name>
  <summary>&lt;p&gt;Only qualified professionals can conduct learning disability assessments. Professionals can select, administer, and interpret a variety of neurological, psychological, educational, and vocational assessment instruments, as appropriate. If a local program does not have access to a qualified professional, adult educators can consider the following national organizations and online resources to find local professional referrals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; (graphic) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="AltTag"&gt;Alt Tag: Young smiling man&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://dyslexiaida.org" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The International Dyslexia Association&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a non-profit organization dedicated to helping individuals with dyslexia, their families, and the communities that support them. The International Dyslexia Association provides resources in the following areas: information and referral services, research, advocacy and public policy, and professional development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ldaamerica.org/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Learning Disabilities Association of America&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/a&gt;is the largest non-profit volunteer organization advocating for individuals with LD. The Learning Disabilities Association of America’s resources include services designed to support and promote the success of individuals with LD, collaborative activities, and position papers on critical issues. This organization also provides a clear&lt;a href="https://ldaamerica.org/adult-learning-disability-assessment-process/" target="_blank"&gt; overview of the disability assessment process for adult learners&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ldonline.org" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;LD Online &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;features articles, multimedia, monthly columns by noted experts, first person essays, a comprehensive resource guide, forums, and a Yellow Pages referral directory of professionals, schools, and products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to ask potential testers about their experiences and specializations before referring a learner who exhibits behaviors or symptoms of a learning disability for further evaluation. Do they have experience with evaluating ELLs? Also ask about the test being administered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of an evaluation can range from hundreds to thousands of dollars, based on the evaluator and battery of tests provided. Some state Vocational Rehabilitation Programs provide funding for evaluations. To find out more about Vocational Rehabilitation Services visit T&lt;a href="https://www.nationalrehab.org" target="_blank"&gt;he National Rehabilitation Association. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence></sequence>
  <visible>0</visible>
  <availabilityjson>$@NULL@$</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>0</timemodified>
</section>