<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="193" moduleid="8454" modulename="book" contextid="35830">
  <book id="193">
    <name>Screening and Testing</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;This section explores identifying, screening, and evaluating learning disabilities.  &lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1547482217</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1547491383</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1300">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Introduction to ELL Screening Instruments</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;A learning disability can make learning English difficult for some ELLs. However, it is not always clear if an ELL has a LD. This is why it is important to screen ELL students who appear to have a learning disability. Based on the findings, instructors can then determine if a formal diagnostic evaluation performed by a professional is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will continue by reviewing freely available, validated screening and diagnostic evaluation tools for ELLs appearing to have a LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/asian%20man.jpg" alt="A young Asian man sits in a classroom in front of a laptop and looks out of frame." width="500" height="334" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Photo Credit:&amp;nbsp;Zephyr18 Stock Photo ID: 874616358&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551243149</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1301">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Characteristics of effective screening instruments</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;When screening for LDs in ELLs, the goal is not to determine the learner's academic strengths and weaknesses in each skill area, but to provide a rough estimate of the learners' overall skill levels.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features of effective LD screening instruments include :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Helpful in determining the need for future testing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inexpensive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick to administer, score, and interpret&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appropriate for large numbers of persons and may sometimes be administered in group settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Narrow in purpose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Able to provide a superficial assessment of several areas, such as language, motor, or social skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usable without extensive training of staff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/2%20women.jpg" width="600" height="400" alt="A woman reviews a paper document with another woman wearing a hijab. They are in a library."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Photo Credit: MonkeyBusinessImages Stock Photo ID: 600000530&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551243169</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1302">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Sample LD screening questions</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Let's take a quick look at a sample LD screening tool. The sample questions below were taken from the &lt;a href="https://www.dshs.wa.gov/esa/social-services-manual/learning-disabilities-and-deficits" target="_blank"&gt;Washington State Learning Needs Screening Tool&lt;/a&gt;, which is a public domain tool.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tool is validated for English speakers only, not ELLs. What challenges do you think screeners may experience when using the tool on ELL students?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5&gt;Sample questions from the Washington Tool&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Did you have any problems learning in middle school or junior high school?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do you have difficulty or experience problems with arithmetic signs (+/x)?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do you have difficulty remembering how to spell simple words you&amp;nbsp; know?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do you have difficulty or experience problems taking notes?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/wash%20tool_page.png" alt="A screenshot of the Washington State Learning Needs Screening Tool." width="327" height="386" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551243194</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1303">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Possible causes of screening inaccuracies</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Translators who use the Washington State Screening Tool with ELL students should be mindful of the possibility of inaccuracies in translated responses. For example, inaccuracies may occur when a family member who is translating sees a need to shield the individual being screened.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the use of screening questions regarding school history may be limited since school attendance can have different meanings in different cultures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="0" style="background-color: #d0d0d6; ; width: 500px;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;More Information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a validated&amp;nbsp;tool available for Spanish speakers called the &lt;a href="http://www.ldanys.org/images/uploads/misc/1317565284_Empire%20State%20Screen.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Empire State Screen: Learning Needs Screen for Spanish-Speaking Adults&lt;/a&gt;. This tool was developed through the Learning Disabilities Association of Western New York. Additional resources for using this tool are available from the &lt;a href="http://www.ldanys.org/index.php?s=4&amp;amp;b=13&amp;amp;p=16" target="_blank"&gt;Learning Disabilities Association of New York State&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/LDA.png" alt="Learning Disabilities Association of Western New York logo" width="344" height="131" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565883942</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1304">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Diagnostic evaluation reports</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;If a screening session indicates that an ELL may have a learning disability, the next step is performing a diagnostic evaluation. Remember, screening only indicates the likelihood of a learning disability, so it is critical that a follow-up diagnostic evaluation is completed to determine if a disability truly exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to screenings, diagnostic tests are available in Spanish with the use of a translator if the psychologist is not fluent in Spanish. Again, keep in mind that the translator should only be used if their responses will be unbiased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A learning disability diagnostic report can offer a wide variety of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Report details may include some or all of the following information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear and specific identification of a learning disability stated in the documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation of a developmental and educational history consistent with a learning disability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standardized measures of academic achievement and cognitive processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functional limitation(s) in one or more of the following areas of academic achievement:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="Bullet"&gt;Reading (decoding, fluency, and comprehension)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="Bullet"&gt;Mathematics (calculations, math fluency, and applied reasoning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="Bullet"&gt;Written Language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation of relative strength(s) in academic achievement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation that shows alternative explanations for the academic limitations have been considered and ruled out (e.g., low cognitive ability, lack of adequate instruction, and emotional factors, such as anxiety or depression)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation of weaknesses and strengths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recommendation on accommodations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547486435</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1305">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Help for performing diagnostic evaluations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Only qualified professionals can conduct learning disability assessments. Professionals can select, administer, and interpret a variety of neurological, psychological, educational, and vocational assessment instruments, as appropriate. If a local program does not have access to a qualified professional, adult educators can consider the following national organizations and online resources to find local professional referrals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://dyslexiaida.org" target="_blank"&gt;The International Dyslexia Association&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is a non-profit organization dedicated to helping individuals with dyslexia, their families, and the communities that support them. The International Dyslexia Association provides resources in the following areas: information and referral services, research, advocacy and public policy, and professional development.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ldaamerica.org/" target="_blank"&gt;The Learning Disabilities Association of America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is the largest non-profit volunteer organization advocating for individuals with LD. The Learning Disabilities Association of America’s resources include services designed to support and promote the success of individuals with LD, collaborative activities, and position papers on critical issues. This organization also provides a clear &lt;a href="https://ldaamerica.org/adult-learning-disability-assessment-process/" target="_blank"&gt;overview of the disability assessment process for adult learners&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ldonline.org" target="_blank"&gt;LD Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; features articles, multimedia, monthly columns by noted experts, first person essays, a comprehensive resource guide, forums, and a Yellow Pages referral directly of professionals, schools, and products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to ask potential testers about their experiences and specializations before referring a &lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/smiling%20man.png" alt="A smiling man " width="201" height="294" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_left"&gt;learner who exhibits behaviors or symptoms of a learning disability for further evaluation. Do they have experience with evaluating ELLs? Also ask about the test being administered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cost of an evaluation can range from hundreds to thousands of dollars, based on the evaluator and battery of tests provided. Some state Vocational Rehabilitation Programs provide funding for evaluations. To find out more about Vocational Rehabilitation Services, visit &lt;a href="https://www.nationalrehab.org" target="_blank"&gt;The National Rehabilitation Association&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565884074</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1306">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Case Study 1: Felipe</title>
        <content>&lt;h4&gt;Why is Felipe struggling?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s review a quick case study to help you reflect on the ELL students that may walk through your door.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="0" style="border-color: #ffffff; border-width: 0px; background-color: #d3d3d3; width: 550px; border-style: solid;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Felipe is a 19-year-old born in Mexico. When he was 12 years old, he moved to the United States with his family. He has two brothers and one sister, and has always been interested in becoming a firefighter, but first wants to increase his English skills to help him better communicate with co-workers. His education has been in Mexico and the United States. However, his schooling was frequently interrupted by moves. Felipe did not finish high school; he grew up speaking Spanish and limited English; and he reports reading problems in both Spanish and English. Felipe is currently enrolled in an adult basic education class.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Felipe_cropped.jpg" alt="Photo of a young man and a woman sitting together with a map of Mexico in the background." width="300" height="326" class="atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Felipe&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;19 -year-old born in Mexico&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Three siblings&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interested in becoming a firefighter&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Education in Mexico and U.S.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moved frequently&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Did not finish high school&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grew up speaking Spanish and limited English&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reports reading problems in Spanish and English&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Currently enrolled in adult basic education class&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;Based on this information, can you determine why Felipe is struggling in both English and Spanish?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;If you said no, that's correct! While you&amp;nbsp;have gathered some important background information on Felipe's family, schooling, and aspirations, more information is needed to determine why Felipe is struggling and whether or not he has a learning disability.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons adult ELLs, like Felipe, struggle to learn English. These struggles cannot always be attributed to a learning disability and need to be looked into further through screening and a diagnostic evaluation.&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551124078</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1307">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Case Study 2: Abdul</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Let's review another case study to help us consider the difficulties associated with screening and testing ELLs for LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="0" style="background-color: #d3d3d3; ; width: 550px;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;Abdul is a 32-year-old who has recently moved to the United States. While attending elementary and secondary school in Iraq, he had problems with reading and writing Arabic, his native language. He also struggled to learn English and never completed high school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="MoreInfoBox"&gt;Abdul has two sisters who never experienced any learning problems. However, this is not the case for Abdul. He has been trying to increase his reading proficiency by participating in an adult education class, but his progress has been very slow. He is frustrated and is considering dropping out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/abdul_cropped.jpg" alt="Photo of a hand writing in Arabic script with a map of Iran in the background." width="300" height="319" class="atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Abdul&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;32-year-old who recently moved to the U.S.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Problems with reading and writing Arabic (native language) and learning English&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Did not complete high school&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sisters never experienced learning problems&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Participating in an adult education class, but progress has been slow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Case Study Question&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the information you have about Abdul, should you recommend an LD assessment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you think you should not recommend an LD assessment at this time, you are correct. More information about Abdul is needed before recommending an LD assessment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551124120</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1308">
        <pagenum>9</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Information needed to recommend an LD assessment</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;What else do you think you should know before recommending an LD assessment for Abdul?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How strong are Abdul’s English language and literacy skills?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How strong are Abdul's English language and literacy skills?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kinds of problems did he have with reading and writing in Arabic?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long ago did he complete his last year of school in Iraq?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of the above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you selected all of the above, you are correct! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the listed items would be good questions to ask before recommending an LD assessment. In addition, you may consider the following questions on screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the similarities and differences between schooling in Iraq and in the U.S.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How would a diagnosis of LD affect Abdul? Could it be a source of shame? Or a helpful explanation of a problem that could lead to accommodations to help him learn better?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What were the English classes he took in Iraq like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How long has Abdul lived in the U.S.?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does Abdul practice speaking English outside of class? If so, how much?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does he practice reading and writing English outside of class? If so, how much?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only when you have gained enough knowledge through informal observations and asking questions should you move forward with recommending a formal assessment.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547490882</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1309">
        <pagenum>10</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Challenges associated with testing an adult ELL for LD</title>
        <content>&lt;p class="Subhead"&gt;As demonstrated through case studies, there are many questions we should ask before recommending an ELL receive a formal assessment for LD. By doing so, we can determine if there are true benefits and advantages of moving forward with an assessment and, in some cases, avoid or reduce some of the challenges associated with testing adult ELLs for LD. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several testing challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of information.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; We have identified very little research on adult ELLs with diagnosed LD. Theories and norms that describe the normal process of language and literacy development in ELLs have yet to be established. Without an understanding of normal development, determining what might be considered evidence of LD in an ELL is very difficult.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influence of prior schooling and individual/social factors.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; The role of school in influencing language development is recognized, but not well understood. Individual and social factors also influence language development in critical, but poorly understood, ways.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complex relationship between language and learning.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; The relationship between language and learning is complex and difficult to test. Limited language proficiency in English may prevent learning or mask an LD at the root of learning problems. Limited language proficiency may cause learners to perform poorly on assessments used to identify LD.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lack of assessment reliability.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt; There are many risks associated with testing ELLs for LD that impact the reliability of the results. These risks include:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessments are mostly in English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessments may not be culturally appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assessments are normed on English-speaking children, not adults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personnel administering the assessments may not be qualified&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547491239</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>