<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="195" moduleid="8456" modulename="book" contextid="35832">
  <book id="195">
    <name>Instructional Strategies</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;We wrap up this lesson by exploring our fourth and final guiding question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are some strategies for teaching ELLs with possible or identified LD?&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1547492226</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1547492226</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1315">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Elements of a comprehensive evaluation</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;What are some strategies for teaching ELLs with possible or identified LD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instructors of adult ELLs may wonder whether a certain student has a learning disability that is impeding his or her progress in English. Yet many of us work in settings where we do not have ready access to consultation, guidance, or referral advice and special needs professionals to address these concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To further complicate the classroom setting, language challenges are exacerbated for ELL students with LD because they are struggling not just in one, but two different languages.  The responsibility then falls on teachers to make sure the classroom environment is not the cause for learning breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic includes some suggestions of what an instructor can do when teaching to a culturally and linguistically diverse class.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547492496</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1316">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Strategies for teaching a diverse class of ELLs with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Here are a few classroom strategies instructors can employ when teaching a linguistically and culturally diverse class of adult ELL students with LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce the level of distraction in the room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide additional time whenever possible. Students with LD may require extra time to complete in-class and homework assignments as well as tests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consider administering tests in alternative formats, such as orally or on the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whenever appropriate, present material using graphics and/or sensory media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine both auditory and visual stimuli when possible. For example, say directions &amp;nbsp;and write them on the board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have students use a word processor to whatever extent is possible. Because word processing makes rewriting and revising so much less laborious, its value is immeasurable for those students with fine-motor, sequencing, spelling, and other language manipulation problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make it easy for students to ask for repetition and bear in mind that it is important to use the same language when you do repeat so that you do not change the construction and defeat the purpose of the repetition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow time in advance for students to think about items to be covered in class. Provide plenty of pre-discussion, pre-writing, pre-reading lead time, and other pre-teaching activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't jump without warning from one topic to another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly state the topic at hand and proceed in a structured, concrete manner. Progress from the obvious to the concrete to the abstract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frame material by relating it to past classroom or personal experience and always highlight new material.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't issue too many instructions at the same time. Break tasks down into their component parts and issue the instructions for each part one at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="Bullet"&gt;Have you used any of these strategies in your classroom instruction with ELLs with LDs? If so, share your experiences in the LINCS Community of Practice &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/english-language-acquisition" target="_blank"&gt;English Language Acquisition&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/disabilities-and-equitable-outcomes" target="_blank"&gt;Disabilities and Equitable Outcomes&lt;/a&gt; groups.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565808202</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1317">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Assistive technology</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;In addition to the instructional strategies you just reviewed, assistive technology can help improve functional capabilities of students with LD.&amp;nbsp; It can help ELLs with LD accomplish daily living tasks assisting them in communication, education, work, and recreational activities. In essence, assistive technology helps them achieve greater independence and enhance their quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the definition proposed in the Assistive Technology Act of 1998, "Assistive, or adaptive, technology commonly refers to products, devices, or equipment, whether acquired commercially, modified, or customized, that are used to maintain, increase, or improve the functional capabilities of individuals with disabilities..."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto; float: right;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/act.png?time=1551122389778" alt="A dictionary with text next to it reading : Assistive Technology Act of 1998... &amp;quot;Assistive, or adaptive, technology commonly refers to products, devices, or equipment, whether acquired commercially, modified, or customized, that are used to maintain, increase, or improve the functional capabilities of individuals with disabilities...&amp;quot;" width="740" height="371" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_right"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551243463</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1318">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Examples of assistive technology</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of assistive technology that can be used in an instructional classroom setting.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When using a computer, many ELLs with LD may find it helpful to use reading assistive technology software, such as a screen reader.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A screen reader is a software application that converts text to speech by reading the written contents of a computer screen. There are a variety of screen readers designed for specific operating systems. An example of free screen reader software is available from &lt;a href="https://www.nvaccess.org/" target="_blank"&gt;NV Access&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ELLs with LD may find it helpful to use talking word prediction software when typing on a computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used along with standard writing software, talking Word prediction software can be beneficial to instruction. These programs use speech synthesizers to provide auditory feedback of what is typed. They also suggest words for you to use as you type and provide spoken feedback to help you find mistakes. This can help ELLS with LD that experience problems with writing and editing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/assistivetech.jpg" width="550" height="367" alt="A young woman uses assistive technology that connects her phone and a pen. "&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551243941</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1319">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Language proficiency</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;WIOA requires states to “align content standards with state-adopted challenging content standards.” English language proficiency standards are one essential component of a state-adopted standards approach. While each state determines the set of the standards appropriate for the state, the U.S. Department of Education supported the development of &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-964%20" target="_blank"&gt;English Language Proficiency (ELP) Standards for Adult Education&lt;/a&gt; as one option to address the need for educational equity, access, and rigor for ELLs. ELP Standards are essential to ensure that adult ELLs receive the focused and effective instruction needed to access states’ academic content standards and ultimately acquire the language, knowledge, and skills necessary for success in postsecondary and career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="0" style="background-color: #d3d3d3; ; width: 550px;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Explore Federal ELP Standards Resources&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department of Education has developed many resources designed to assist states in the implementation of ELP standards, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;English Language Proficiency Standards for Adult Education. This report is intended to support all educators who are teaching adult ELLs, including ELLs with disabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A series of three online modules:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-1049%20" target="_blank"&gt;Introduction to the English Language Proficiency Standards for Adult Education –Module One&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-1105%20" target="_blank"&gt;Analyzing Student Tasks in Relation to Content Demands, Thinking Skills, and Language Use – Module Two&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-1106%20" target="_blank"&gt;Digging Deeper into the English Language Proficiency Standards for Adult Education – Module Three&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551123055</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1320">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>ELLs with LD have specific instructional needs</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;ELLs with disabilities have specific instructional needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ELP Standards for Adult Education have ten guiding principals that informed the development of the standards. Guiding principal #8 acknowledges that ELLs with disabilities have specific instructional needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="638" valign="top"&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Adult ELLs have the potential to meet state-adopted challenging academic content standards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Adult ELLs represent a diverse population of learners.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Adult ELLs’ funds of knowledge are a resource for their learning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Social language has an important role in ELLs’ English language acquisition process.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Three key instructional advances form the basis of state-adopted content standards for English language arts in adult education that ELLs must access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Adult ELLs must be able to successfully engage with a wide variety of informational texts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Scaffolding is an essential tool to facilitate ELLs’ acquisition of language and content.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;ELLs with disabilities have specific instructional needs.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Multimedia technology aligned to the ELP Standards for AE should be integrated into instruction.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Academic language instruction should be incorporated into all content lessons, including mathematics and science.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Source: U.S. Department of Education, Office of Career, Technical and Adult Education. Adult English Language Proficiency Standards for Adult Education. Washington, DC, 2016.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Bullet"&gt;The ELP Standards for Adult Education report provides some examples of instructional supports that can serve as accommodations for adult ELLs with learning disabilities. These supports and scaffolding recommendations by level are shown below. While these supports are not necessarily intended for adult ELLs with learning disabilities, many of these strategies support a classroom environment that is supportive and inclusive of adult ELLs with LD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table&gt;&lt;caption&gt;Table C-1. Supports and Scaffolding Recommendations by Level&lt;/caption&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="col"&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="col"&gt;ELP Levels&amp;nbsp; 1-2&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="col"&gt;ELP Levels 3-4&lt;/th&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="col"&gt;ELP Level 5&amp;nbsp;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="row"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Teacher Language and Teacher-Student Exchanges&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Give wait time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use contextualized language about concrete topics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Repeat, paraphrase, model, and gesture&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use think alouds to model processes and language&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Give one-step directions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use native language as appropriate&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have students demonstrate understanding by pointing or gesturing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Concentrate on meaning rather than correctness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Give wait time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use contextualized language about concrete and abstract topics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Repeat, paraphrase and model&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use think alouds to model processes and language&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Concentrate on meaning rather than correctness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Model complex grammatical language about both concrete and abstract topics&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="row"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Materials and Activities&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build background&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use visuals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use total physical response (TPR)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use graphic organizers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use illustrations and photos to show student understanding&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use native language texts or ELP level-appropriate texts as a supplement to complex texts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Purposefully teach vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide bilingual glossaries&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide word/phrase cards with photo or illustration for definition&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide audio books (in English and native language) to support content learning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide sentence starters and frames&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Draw and label or write words/short sentences&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complete vocabulary log with images&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build background&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use visuals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use TPR&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use graphic organizers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use acting or role plays to demonstrate student understanding&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use native language texts or ELP level-appropriate texts as a supplement to complex texts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Purposefully teach vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide bilingual glossaries&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide word/phrase cards with photo or illustration for definition&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide audio books (in English and native language) to support content learning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide word/phrase banks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide sentence starters and frames&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Build background&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use visuals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use TPR&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use graphic organizers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Purposefully teach vocabulary&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide bilingual glossaries&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provide audio books (in English) to support content learning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Analyze complex grammatical language about both concrete and abstract topics&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th style="border: 1px solid gray;" scope="row"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student Groupings&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Partner work (with additional scaffolds)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Small groups (with teacher support and additional scaffolds)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Partner work (with additional scaffolds)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Small groups (with additional scaffolds)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td style="border: 1px solid gray;"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Partner work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Small groups&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Source: U.S. Department of Education. (2016). English Language Proficiency Standards for Adult Education. Retrieved from https://lincs.ed.gov/publications/pdf/elp-standards-adult-ed.pdf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Bullet"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ascd.org/ascd-express/vol8/802-carr.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;Explore strategies for teaching English learners with learning disabilities.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565808272</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>