<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="2378">
  <number>37</number>
  <name>Glossary</name>
  <summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="1" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Term&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Definition&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult basic education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult basic education generally refers to the instructional programming delivered to adult learners at a grade level equivalent (GLE) of 1-8.9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult secondary education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adult secondary education generally refers to the instructional programming delivered to adult learners at a grade level equivalent (GLE) of 9.0-11.9.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English Language Acquisition Program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WIOA Section 203(6) defines English language acquisition programs as a program of instruction designed to help eligible individuals who are ELLs achieve competence in reading, writing, speaking, and comprehension of the English language and that leads to attainment of a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent; and transition to postsecondary education and training; or employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;English Language Learners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WIOA Section 203(7) defines English language learners to describe individuals who has limited ability in reading, writing, speaking or comprehending the English language and whose native language is a language other than English, or who lives in a family or community environment where a language other than English is the dominant language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrated Education and Training&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Integrated Education and Training (IET) program must meet the definition and requirements set forth in WIOA 34 CFR Part 463 Subpart D and the final regulations as established by the Department of Education on August 19, 2016 in the Federal Register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IET is a service approach that provides adult education and literacy activities concurrently and contextually with workforce preparation activities and workforce training for a specific occupation or occupational cluster for the purpose of educational and career advancement (ยง463.35). An IET program must include the following three components: adult education and literacy activities, workforce preparation activities, and workforce training (ยง463.36). In addition, as part of a career pathway (ยง463.37), the design of an IET program should support the local and state workforce development board plans as required under WIOA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td width="163" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Integrated English Literacy and Civics Education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td width="451" valign="top"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An IELCE program must meet the definition and requirements set forth in WIOA 34 CFR Part 463 Subpart G and the final regulations as published by the Department of Education on August 19, 2016 in the Federal Register.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IELCE provides education services to English language learners who are adults, including professionals with degrees and credentials in their native countries, that enables such adults to achieve competency in the English language and acquire the basic and more advanced skills needed to function effectively as parents, workers, and citizens in the United States. Such services must include instruction in literacy and English language acquisition and instruction on the rights and responsibilities of citizenship and civic participation. The funds provided under section 243 of the Act must be used in combination with integrated education and training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence></sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availabilityjson>$@NULL@$</availabilityjson>
  <timemodified>0</timemodified>
</section>