<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="194" moduleid="8455" modulename="book" contextid="35831">
  <book id="194">
    <name>Testing Considerations</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;This section of the course will explore the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a learner and instructor choose to explore the option of testing for LD, what considerations should an instructor bear in mind?&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1547491352</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1547492055</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1310">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Case Study 3: Lieu</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;The next case study involves an adult ELL who is being considered for LD testing. Her story will help us prepare to explore considerations when testing for LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a learner and instructor choose to explore the option of testing for LD, what considerations should an instructor bear in mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table border="0" style="border-color: #ffffff; border-width: 0px; background-color: #d3d3d3; width: 550px; border-style: solid;"&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Lieu is a 24-year-old who moved to the U.S. when she was 18 years old. She did not complete high school and has no formal education, but studied some English.&amp;nbsp; Lieu aspires to work as a medical technician, but needs to pass the GED before she can progress with her studies.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/lieu_cropped.jpg" alt="Photo of a young Asian woman smiling with a map of Vietnam in the background." width="355" height="340" class="img-responsive atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Lieu&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;24 years old&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Moved to U.S. at 18 years old&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Studied some English, but no formal education&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Did not complete high school&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aspirations to work as a medical technician, but needs to pass the GED&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Case Study Question&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on what you know, should Lieu receive accommodations when taking the GED? Accommodations, as defined by the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA), are modifications or adjustments to the tasks, environments, or way things are done in order to enable individuals with disabilities to have an equal opportunity for participation. Think about your answer, then click the forward arrow to explore this topic further.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551124016</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1311">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Accommodations for examinations</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Since Lieu does not have a documented learning disability, she is not eligible to receive accommodations on the GED. This is because when it comes to the GED, which is covered under the Americans with Disabilities Act Amendments Act of 2008, no accommodations are provided unless a disability is documented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Lieu wants to take the GED, and she and her teacher are seriously concerned that her performance may be compromised without accommodations, Lieu will need to be evaluated for a learning disability. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chief Examiner may permit Lieu to use the following adaptations and devices without prior approval from the GED Administrator, GED Testing Service, or GEDTS trained and certified personnel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear transparent overlays and highlighter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Temporary adhesive (e.g., Post-it Notes) with spatial directions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earplugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large print test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Magnifying glass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One test per day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straightedge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or other devices as deemed appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When ELLs like Lieu plan on being evaluated for LD, there are several important considerations to bear in mind.  We'll continue by taking a look at the top considerations. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547491619</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1312">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Considerations when testing for LD</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Before referring an adult ELL for an evaluation, adult education professionals should carefully consider if the adult will benefit from such an evaluation.&amp;nbsp; A diagnosis of LD might lead to more directed intervention or specific accommodations on high-stakes tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The identification of LD during elementary or secondary schooling is not a binding determination of&amp;nbsp;services at the postsecondary level.&amp;nbsp; Without the documentation to support the request, many of these individuals will not be able to receive accommodations, particularly on high-stakes tests such as the GED or professional licensure examinations. However, one of the greatest barriers to the adult ELL obtaining a comprehensive evaluation is the increasingly high cost of such evaluations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key consideration is the quality of assessment, and ensuring the professional conducting the assessment is qualified. We'll talk more about this on the following screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Key considerations:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Purpose of assessment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cost of assessment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quality of assessment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551120216</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1313">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Evaluation qualifications</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;There are a limited number of evaluators with the expertise to evaluate ELLs for LD.&amp;nbsp; The qualifications of the professional conducting the assessment should be carefully considered to ensure the ELL receives a thorough and accurate assessment. Some of the qualifications an evaluator should have include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experience with the culture of the ELL, including the norms in the mother country and local community;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;appropriate credentials to conduct a comprehensive assessment;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experience evaluating adolescents and adults with LD; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fluency in both English and the native language of the examinee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="max-width:100%; height:auto;" src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/qualifications.png" alt="A clipboard with a &amp;quot;Qualifications of a Comprehensive Evaluator&amp;quot; checklist on it which reads: Experience with the culture of the ELL, including the norms in the mother country and local community; appropriate credentials to conduct a comprehensive assessment; experience evaluating adolescents and adults with LD; and fluency in both English and the native language of the examinee." width="550" height="295" class="atto_image_button_text-bottom"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1551243415</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1314">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Elements of a comprehensive evaluation</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;If an ELL elects to be evaluated for an LD to obtain accommodations, it is important that the evaluation is thorough and fair. A comprehensive evaluation includes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consideration of the native language;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;consideration of the target language;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data to support the language of assessment;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;valid and reliable assessment measures;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;specific cognitive and language processing areas assessed;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;professional judgment critical to any decision making; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recommendations for accommodations. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547491939</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>