<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="197" moduleid="8459" modulename="book" contextid="35835">
  <book id="197">
    <name>Conclusion</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You have completed the &lt;em&gt;Learning to Achieve Learning Disabilities and English Language Learners &lt;/em&gt;online course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now understand the prevalence of ELLs;  be able to describe the challenges they face in learning English; identify key considerations when screening and testing ELLs who may have a learning disability; and describe instructional classroom strategies for teaching ELLs with possible or diagnosed learning disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>1</numbering>
    <navstyle>1</navstyle>
    <customtitles>0</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1547496070</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1547496070</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="1323">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Participate in the LINCS Community</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! You have completed the &lt;em&gt;Learning to Achieve Learning Disabilities and English Language Learners&lt;/em&gt; online course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should now understand the prevalence of ELLs;  be able to describe the challenges they face in learning English; identify key considerations when screening and testing ELLs who may have a learning disability; and describe instructional classroom strategies for teaching ELLs with possible or diagnosed learning disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage you to stay involved in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Community&lt;/a&gt; and the L&lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/group/disabilities-adult-education" target="_blank"&gt;INCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; as you strive to help the adult ELL students with LD in your classroom be more independent and improve their language acquisition skills. We also encourage you to discuss and apply your newly acquired knowledge and learn about others' experiences in supporting adult ELLs with LD.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1547496174</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1324">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Evaluation and certificate</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;This concludes the &lt;i&gt;Learning Disabilities and English Language Learners&lt;/i&gt; course. We would like to thank Juliana Taymans, who generously contributed to the design and development of this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that we can maintain the quality of our courses, we ask that you take a moment to complete the&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.surveygizmo.com/s3/5159793/Learning-to-Achieve-English-Language-Learners-Training-Module" target="_blank"&gt;course evaluation&lt;/a&gt;. Your feedback will ensure our courses meet your needs for professional development. Thank you.&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;span&gt;Access and Print Your Certificate at Any Time:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on completing this LINCS Learning to Achieve course, &lt;i&gt;Learning Disabilities and English Language Learners&lt;/i&gt;. To obtain your completion certificate, simply close this window and return to the course homepage. You will find a link for the completion certificate under the Course Conclusion and Resources section header.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565808424</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="1325">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>References</title>
        <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following references were used to develop this course.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bergen, K. (2006). How 4 people turned learning disabilities into stories of success, fortune and happiness. Chicago, IL: Chicago Tribune. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.allkindsofminds.org/" target="_blank"&gt;www.allkindsofminds.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brown, D. (2004). Learning to work: A story by a learning disabled person. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.ldresources.org/" target="_blank"&gt;www.ldresources.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brown, D. (2009). Self-help for learning disabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carr, J. (2012). Strategies for teaching English learners and students with learning disabilities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Working with Challenging Students&lt;/i&gt;, 8(2). Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.ascd.org/ascd-express/vol8/802-carr.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.ascd.org/ascd-express/vol8/802-carr.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Conference Board, Inc., the Partnership for 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;nbsp;Century Skills, Corporate Voices for Working Families, and the Society for Human Resource Management. (2006). Are they really ready to work? Employers’ Perspectives on the Basic Knowledge and Applied Skills of New Entrants to the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;nbsp;Century U.S. Workforce. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.p21.org/storage/documents/FINAL_REPORT_PDF09-29-06.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.p21.org/storage/documents/FINAL_REPORT_PDF09-29-06.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Covington, L. E. (2004). Moving beyond the limits of learning: Implications of learning disabilities for adult education. Adult Basic Education: An Interdisciplinary Journal for Adult Literacy Educational Planning, 14(2), 90-103.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dickinson, D. L. and Verbeek, R. L. (2002). Wage differentials between college graduates with and without learning disabilities. Journal of Learning Disabilities, 35, 175-184&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gerber, P.J., &amp;amp; Price, L.A. (2003) Persons with learning disabilities in the workplace: What we know so far in the Americans with Disabilities Act era. Learning Disabilities: Research &amp;amp; Practice, 18(2), 132-136.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gregg, N. (2007). Underserved and unprepared: Postsecondary learning disabilities. Learning Disabilities Research &amp;amp; Practice, 2 2(4) [sic], 219-228.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning Disabilities Association of America. (n.d). Adult learning disability process. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://ldaamerica.org/adult-learning-disability-assessment-process/" target="_blank"&gt;https://ldaamerica.org/adult-learning-disability-assessment-process/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OECD (2013), Time for the U.S. to reskill?: What the survey of adult skills says, OECD Skills Studies, OECD Publishing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264204904-en" target="_blank"&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/9789264204904-en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reder, S. (2014). The impact of ABS Program Participation on Long-Term Economic Outcomes. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-780" target="_blank"&gt;https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-780&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. Department of Education (2016). English Language Proficiency Standards for Adult Education. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/publications/pdf/elp-standards-adult-ed.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;https://lincs.ed.gov/publications/pdf/elp-standards-adult-ed.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;U.S. Departments of Labor, Commerce, Educcation, and Health and Human Services. (2014). What works in job training: A synthesis of the evidence. Retrieved from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.dol.gov/asp/evaluation/jdt/jdt.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;http://www.dol.gov/asp/evaluation/jdt/jdt.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1565882976</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
    <chaptertags>
    </chaptertags>
  </book>
</activity>